Okay, we're now wanting to move into regular city council meeting for today's day.
Adam too is public input and schedule personal parameters.
The only audience that wishes to address the council on any of the agenda items.
And there being none out of three is consent agenda staff is recommending items for three seven for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on either of those items, we'll enter a motion to approve.
May I write a motion to approve items?
Pour two seven on the consent agenda.
And a second.
I'll second it.
Will call please.
Johnson.
Lewis time.
Weston.
Forester.
All right.
I'm going to read item eight that I'm asking you to come in on it.
Item eight is a mid demolition permanent application requiring proof of insurance.
Name in the city as an additional insured and proof of what this compensation insurance
or an average of an exemption and a $50,000 performance blind executed by the contractor.
I said being.
Well, actually that's correct.
The first is going to do the presentation on the side of it.
But one thing I did want to ask the council about.
This is not a time certain item.
And I want to compliment Christy and Ben on the work that they've done on this.
I've supported 100%.
But what we're giving you this evening is basically the approval of about a five page document.
And generally speaking, I don't like to do that.
At a council meeting, right, just hand you something that's that long and ask you to approve it.
So what I'd like to do is ask Christy and Ben to get the presentation of this is about.
But then if you'd like to think about it a little bit, we can put this on another agenda for actual approval.
So I just, I never want to pitch it a position unless we really have to approve a long document where you haven't had it.
It was just given to you tonight.
So that's basically it.
I know a lot of good work has gone into this.
Okay.
Christy?
So what this is, a few years back, a project started here at the city to revise the demo permit application.
The current demo permit application is very simple.
And it's much like another building permit application.
So there's just a couple of questions asked.
And it's reviewed, no plans are submitted or anything like that.
And then it signed off on.
And what I understand a few years ago, it was decided that we needed to strengthen our demo permit application to include the addition of exactly what the requirements are for a demo contractor.
Because when you're demo property, you can't just take it there and then, you know, discard of the debris.
It has to be brought back to a mobile surface, the point of, you know, exactly where it's at.
So there's certainly requirements that get a body, whether it's a public.
or private demo that have to be met.
So the demo permit was revised to include those requirements,
which are in our ordinances,
it's something that's always been there,
but making sure that when they sign the application,
they understand when they're signing,
they are agreeing to do all of these things
that we require our city contractor to do.
It's part of his build, and he has to take care of that.
The other thing that's different on the demo permit application
is the requirement for a performance bond.
And that was done to help provide a little security
to the city on projects that are larger
that we might need to make sure that if somebody says
they're going to demo a property,
and they start the process that we have some assurance
and whatever end if they take off on during the project
that we've got something to help us finish the project,
if that's the case.
So the way the permit is written is it requires a $50,000 performance bond.
However, the city manager or his or her does it mean
can authorize somebody to wave that bond.
So every contractor that comes in to demo a property will get this,
and we have the ability based on the size of the project,
where the property is at, different things like that,
to decide whether or not they do need a performance bond or not,
but at least we have it written into the application
and they're aware of it at the time that they're filling it out.
So Chris, do you want to use the good Rick's plan as an exam?
I think that's part of what started this.
I guess my concern is, in that example,
what $50,000 have been enough?
No, it's at the $50,000 minimum.
Okay. So it's, I mean, that's going to be part of the discussion
before the application has approved.
Okay. That's part of what has to be talked about
is what those requirements need to be,
whether we wait them because they're not appropriate for somebody
that's demoing a house or whether it needs to be more than $50,000
if it's a bigger project than that.
Okay. And a man that specifically was the project
that we were concerned about when we were looking at drafts.
And so with whom does that discretion look?
He decides the, the sum manager. He can assign that responsibility to someone else,
but in here it says the city manager, he's doesn't mean.
But if a similar situation arose and we felt that a million dollar
before his law was.
necessary, then that's what we would ask for.
Exactly.
Do we always have people go out and inspect
after the demolition?
Or do we have them during the process also?
So I think that was kind of a moves practice before.
I can say that now that demos are in community development,
they go and inspect every property that's demoed.
So after the demo is completed,
they go back and check the property to make sure
that it has had the fill problem that needs
that all the debris is moved from the property
and so that when the grass starts growing,
grass will grow and it is a mobile surface.
So that's something we're going to be more attentive to.
Oh yes, they're required to,
I can tell you right now that they have to inspect every demo.
Yeah, they have to.
Once all of that's done,
check off of, then it turns into a coding
enforcement to keep up with it to make sure that.
Right, grass.
This is issue, yeah.
And if it's one that we demolish, then we follow
the link to concept property.
Yes.
And we had any confines with some of the demolition
as far as, I've seen,
I have, like I said, I haven't got a chance to read this,
but like the best issue,
we had that problem out there.
We had that problem out of Gergriss.
It really brought up as far as the dust.
And we had any confines about that.
About the bridge, as well.
No, we had it.
But we were just, but that was a different kind of.
No, we haven't had any.
I would expect with the EP demo getting ready to start
towards the middle to the end of April.
That's in a real congested business area.
And there's probably going to be some challenges there.
I think the odd thing is we probably have more complaints
with some of the construction that's been taking place
on the vacant loss of the day.
Yes.
I have an agreement.
Okay.
So thank you, Christy.
I would ask that everybody take time
between now and the next council meeting to kind of read through this
and see if you have any questions or concerns or suggestions
if you do.
Yes, certainly call Christy.
Before the end, if you have an opportunity to.
If that the issues.
And then we'll have this as an agenda item for our next meeting.
As I stress, I think they've done a great job on it.
But I just want to give you the time to look at it.
If there's any questions, give you an opportunity to ask.
Okay.
We will then move on to item nine.
Which is Resolution CC-2017.
Dialects are proving community financial support and fee labor
to the Man 2 and 30.
There are a lot of them.
and the structure is located at, as it's listed there,
and Christie that I wish you're named next to it also.
Yes, so this is an economic development
and so if that we're looking at here,
and these pictures were included in their packets.
So, the thing that not a motive is building
the building that's in the top left of the frame there.
That's the building that they're building,
and back behind it is 320B, southeast the blue house,
and that is a house that they have bought,
and that thing on his butt, it is one in detail there,
and bring that property into his business,
so make that area all their part of his business
that he's got, they'll go in on there.
The other pictures that are just kind of giving
an idea of the condition of the home,
or the structure, the property that we're looking at taking down.
So, as in the siloive team,
Mr. Thineland, one of the things that we have talked about
doing the idea for others that came to us with it,
is to demo the structure because this is a home
as you can tell that would be on the demo list anyway.
It's not, and if somebody bought it,
they would have a certain time period to get it secured
in up and running, so most of the time
is just easier to take it down.
So, it's all your property, or looking at it to demo,
and he's willing to do something good with it,
as far as bringing it into his business,
it won't be something that the city has to keep up with,
or know, or try to sell to someone else.
But we'll end up happening, is it will have
a metal privacy fence put around it,
and it'll be storage of that, you know,
some kind of nature for him and his business there.
With the privacy fence, I'll ensure that whatever he stores back there
is within code.
Right, so with our codes, you can have anything in your backyard
that might not look the best,
but you have to have a privacy fence around it.
It can't be visible from the alley, or, you know,
from the neighbors, or something like that.
Chris, I'm just curious, in that first picture
that shows his new building,
there's a blue building to the left, is that the building?
Yeah, I was just trying to show you flexibility.
How close this is to what he's got going on there.
And we actually, Ernst the property now,
he obtained the property in this effort
to bring it into his business.
So he's required the property, and you're asking,
this is part of economic development incentive to him,
to waive the fees related to dumping the infrastructure.
He's saying, I, our city contractor,
like we do on any other demo home that we do.
having him go over and take down the property and level the ground and then what's that down?
He'll Mr. Thillman will come in and do his upgrades to the property.
And do you have a ballpark estimate of the value of that?
Well, the estimate on the Malsh in the House, the the asbestos that everything has already been done
and that didn't come out of the city's pocket, but it's $7,644.
And maybe we look at the off-ability of our viewers suggesting just rating the tipping fees,
but that actually would have caused the city's borer than what this would cost.
Right.
And also I think one of the things in the report is when Mr. Thillman is up and operating with his business,
it will generate about $8,500 in sales taxes per year.
And on top of that, when we did the tipping fee waiver of the policy,
we'll also have a new utility customer, where we did that one there before either.
So the $7,000 cost of the city will be more than made up of over about a two-year period.
And then from there on, we'll have an operating business in town that wasn't here before.
It's very much the line with the comprehensive plan when we think about steep elements
and that being a major third fair and where we, you know,
what we want that to look like going forward and then also removing the evaporated or blight from a residential community.
I think he answered one of my concerns with the fence and the fence is basically going to outline the whole property area where the blue house was.
You know, I think there's a lot of people that could follow Mr. Thillman's lead.
It's going to be a matter to cover up structures that are dilapidated.
You know, and there was a very question, you got a big rule there, what's going on behind it.
But I mean, I think it's a great thing that they're willing to do that to keep.
Sometimes stuff that they're waiting on are fixing.
And we repair it. Yes.
You need concerns.
Is there a set for the fence that goes around that structure?
Is there something set that they have to go buy?
Is it a four foot six foot?
Yeah, it has to be, I believe it's six foot, a six foot metal fence.
Do you know what they have plans for their south main businesses?
For sale? Are they going to?
I'm not sure what their plans are with the south main business.
It'd be moving from there.
Yeah, they're relocating my business.
I'm not sure.
And we were going to tear this down anyway.
Yes.
Yeah, Tommy, obviously that's a man, it's humble.
Yeah.
Go ahead and end this one in red with I actually know that building.
They've been written in 30.
There you go.
In the end.
Time to finish.
I think it's a...
Yeah, it's a general building.
They have minimal space and that building.
Right now.
Well, the building that got there, it looks awesome, and it's being built on a spot
that was just empty before.
Any other questions?
Do we have a motion to approve a resolution CC?
2017 to our show six.
It's my question.
Any second?
A little call.
All right.
For aster?
Johnson?
Lewis?
I've requested.
All right.
Any new business?
Any announcements?
I don't know.
Okay.
If you need to.
So after a staring at yourself, I'll say something about it.
March 4.
March 2.
It was, uh, 11.
10.
It's coming to the other.
7.
Clark.
Red man.
It's going to be good.
It takes March 4.
From 1 to 4.
It has to.
Microwave.
Inside the afternoon.
March 4.
The all-class reunion.
And the beer.
Gidward reunion.
At the same time.
So come out.
It's going to be great.
That's when we're a great day.
It's all right.
And then that evening.
Dennis James and the silent movie.
They call.
Okay.
Any other announcements?
Um, I don't know.
If they haven't been dating, you might touch on this, but uh, this is going to be our last
meeting with Mic.
You're setting up here to help.
So.
It is.
I think we have to go in the way for you next Monday.
Yeah.
Coming up.
So it's kind of having the long goodbye.
And I think it depends on how far on if you're a good daddy.
You're not by then.
Uh, that would be Saturday.
That would be Saturday.
Oh, why?
He's just still handcuffed and balled to you for.
It's Saturday.
Okay.
Yeah.
I think like he's discovering a whole different world now.
Yes.
So, but he's going to be best greatly.
Absolutely.
Thank you for your service.
Thank you, Mic.
Thank you.
No more annoying iPad questions.
I don't find you.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm proud to see you, man.
Between the faces, Dean.
The only thing I wanted to bring up is that next week at four o'clock.
We'll have our study session.
And our plan right now is to talk about completely different way of handling a lot of our
mowing during the year, especially people with vacant lots.
We just talked about that quite a bit.
And looking at trying to bring that back in a house.
So we're much more effective at taking care of this.
So we want to talk about it.
about that with you next week. I may put this item regarding the demolition permit on that, as well as you could think.
Next, excuse me, have that action. I'm trying to get over a cold, I'm sorry.
You're right into the knowing. The issue of buying a motor came up at some point in the past,
and you know, if you had some specific questions, is there anything that you want to make sure they're able to answer
or at next week's meeting, we're like, you know, I think my question in response to your
and certainly correct was in the knowing in regards to the new motor's purchase,
the cemetery.
But we also, cemetery had to help out, and go ahead and pay for that.
That's correct. So, you know, we'll be ready for that.
So, if you're going to be recommending a change in the purchase of machinery and stuff like that,
we'll all know about that.
Okay.
I'm just going to come up under an announcement, I guess.
We, I know we've talked about about public caring for the charter discussion.
We're planning on doing that next month or what you're thinking.
I think I need to get better organized.
I'm sexually saying down the counter today, trying to plot aspects.
I'm going to talk to Rayleigh.
I'm going to talk with the newspaper about getting some more information out.
And then it's drafted some talking points that we're taking a look at right now as you'd requested.
So, I think the term public caring is a bit of a misnolum,
because we've been talking about council meetings for a long time.
But I do want to bring it up again, or have the opportunity,
as we disseminate information for people to give us feedback.
I mean, the artist said, we can't change it at this point,
but I still want people to have the opportunity to ask questions,
so that we can give them, you know, to answer their questions and educate them about it.
I talked to the election board a couple of weeks ago.
My other requirement is that every person that gets about it will get a full copy of the revised charter.
So, we have to prepare 10,000 copies to go to be available.
So, anything else related to that?
No, I don't.
I don't.
We talked about a few weeks ago, and then was going to work on some talking points for worse,
and then we're going to use that as kind of a springboard,
to disseminating information.
Okay.
It is.
Yeah.
They're indicating that's what they do,
and they're getting back with me with a definitive answer.
Okay.
And I talked about the state election board.
As far as I know, the strong impression that that's what is going to be required.
Right.
You have a shoulder or a magnet, it's made of legs.
Okay.
Christian, do you?
Just they did set for publication of the newspaper and it's entirely on Sunday.
Okay.
They're coming Sunday.
26.
Okay.
Now I'll be the first of three.
Correct.
Okay.
Anything else?
What about that?
The first of the three publications is set for the 26.
Crystal is just making sure everyone is aware of that.
Okay.
Anything else?
I have 13 of the gentlemen.
We have most of the gentlemen.
Most of the gentlemen.
Second.
Old Paul, please.
Weston.
Alright.
Forster.
Lewis, I'm souls.
Alright.
We're all done.
D.